Vaibhav Beohar

Portfolio/beohar.com ● GitHub/VBeohar ● LinkedIn/Beohar

Hands-on technology professional with experience in software engineering (front-end and back-end), data science, finance & accounting. Experienced practitioner with proven record in design, development and delivery of complex software systems and machine learning models.

SKILLS

Languages: Python, Java, C++, SQL

Front end scripting languages: HTML5, JavaScript, JSON, CSS, ¡Query, AJAX, D3.js, React.js

Libraries: TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, sklearn, NumPy, Seaborn, pandas, Spacy, Transformers, Java Enterprise Edition (J2EE) Applications and tools: MongoDB, MySQL, Oracle, Snowflake, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Nginx, Gunicorn, Anaplan, Docker containers, Bootstrap, Visual Basic, Google Cloud (GCP), AWS, DataBricks, GitHub, Heroku, MS Office, Atlassian Jira, Trello, Bootstrap Competencies: Full stack development, Design Patterns, Object Oriented Programming, Agile with Scrum, Exploratory Data Analysis, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing (NLP), Deep Learning, Data Engineering, Quantitative methods for statistical analysis, experimental design and causal inference, Financial Modeling, Risk/Planning & Analysis, Corporate Finance, Stakeholder management, Business Analysis, Visualization

EDUCATION

University of California Berkeley; School of Information

Master of Information & Data Science (MIDS) – GPA 3.97

Berkeley, CA August 2022

- Coursework data engineering, statistics, applied machine learning, causal inference & experiments, deep learning on edge devices, natural learning processing with deep learning, data visualization, capstone
- Projects:
 - o Performed Airbnb price prediction using XGBoost, AutoML, neural network & logistic regression
 - Trained deep learning models on IBM cloud and performed inference on Nvidia Jetson TX2 edge devices
 - Created full-stack website using JavaScript, Bootstrap, Flask and Python to display "social network" graph visualizations for the Star Wars movie franchise using D3.js
 - Explored Aspect Based Sentiment Analysis (ABSA) techniques and implemented fine-tuning of RoBERTa, SpanBERT and DistillBERT models to achieve material improvements in aspect extraction and classification tasks
 - Capstone project Created an end-to-end content recommendation analytics product called "MakeSense", to allow emerging streamers on Twitch expand their presence on the platform.
 - Technologies: Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, SQLite, jQuery/Ajax, D3.js, Nginx and Gunicorn, BERT model double fine-tuned on Masked Language Modeling (MLM) and Sentiment Classification tasks

University of Massachusetts Amherst; Isenberg School of Management

Master of Business Administration (MBA) Finance & Accounting – GPA 3.82

Amherst, MA May 2012

Internship (June - Aug 2011): Goldman Sachs – Investment Accounting/Controllers (Jersey City, NJ)

Rajiv Gandhi Technological University

Bhopal, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science (Honors) – GPA 3.75

June 2004

EXPERIENCE

MCKINSEY & COMPANY

Waltham MA/Toronto, ON March 2017— onaoina

Data Scientist & Finance Specialist

- Created unsupervised information extraction NLP model using Python and Google's Universal Sentence Encoder on TensorFlow to implement an internal *search engine* for firm offerings alignment with client media articles using Snowflake, Python and exploratory web technologies like Flask, React, jQuery and D3.js
- Performed monthly maintenance and run of random forest and logistic regression based supervised learning models on R Studio and Python to create predictive probabilities on client churn, win, winback and *most likely* service line offerings, with 90% AUC

- Partnered with data engineers to automate REST API based extraction, transform and load (ETL) jobs and created scripts to
 perform Python, S3, PostGreSQL and Snowflake based multi-threaded data engineering pipelines reducing load times by 5x
- Collaborated on implementing unified snowflake-based feature store for machine learning use-cases and conducted architecture reviews with recommendations on best practices and to create Python based workflows
- Worked on automating firm's annual budgeting and forecasting process into Anaplan (a cloud based EPM platform), spread across 50+ countries and 500+ users; by streamlining headcount, workforce utilization, opex, balance sheet, income statement and other miscellaneous KPI planning thereby improving process efficiencies and user engagement by 250%
- Supervised, coordinated and lead discussions on various ad hoc data science discussions and prospective engagements using project management skills, Agile (with scrum) methodologies and tools such as Jira

GLOBAL ATLANTIC FINANCIAL GROUP

Boston, MA

Associate – Risk, Planning & Analysis

May 2012- March 2017

- Prepared finance materials for CFO, monthly operating committee meetings, quarterly board and risk meetings and other adhoc projects, with timely analysis of various business lines for corporate finance decision making
- Automated legacy Excel models using VBA Macro and SQL for planning, budgeting, and forecasting of short-term and long-term net income of 8 sub- and 1 consolidated entity (\$52bn assets and >300mm operating income); leading to 95% reduction in execution/delivery time compared to prior forecasting models
- Overviewed Actual-to-Expected (A-to-E) variance analysis by cross-functional collaboration with controllers, actuarial, tax and expense teams and by mapping model-to-ledger income statement and balance sheet accounts
- Identified market, regulatory, accounting, and operational items impacting excess capital availability, including:
 - What-if scenario analysis with low/high/baseline test cases and KPIs reported on capital, OpEx and CapEx
 - Risk charges owing to business, interest rate, asset risks, reinsurance, hedges and derivatives
 - \$2bn+ Capital attribution analysis by new business, new sales, net investment income (NII) etc.

GOLDMAN SACHS

New York, NY

April 2007, April 2007

Senior Consultant Programmer

April 2007– Aug 2010

• Developed client-side portfolio management portal (https://marquee.gs.com/) and various trading tools for Goldman Sachs

Asset Management (GSAM) using Java, Unix, Perl, shell scripts, Sybase SQL and various open-source technologies

- Designed and developed a real-time trading solution, as well as an advanced risk model, with timely rollout during the critical Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) to assist the fixed-income trading desk with mortgage-backed security trading, portfolio tracking and performance monitoring tasks using IT tools
- Decommissioned and replaced legacy systems with consolidated web-based system for fixed income insurance desk
- Interacted with external vendors (such as Interactive Data BondEdge) for integrating 3rd party applications for GSAM portfolio management and reporting needs
- Developed, tested, and supported core modules for rollout of GSAM's fixed income insurance advisory system

SIGMA SOFTWARE SOLUTIONS

Pune, India / Toronto, ON

Senior Software Engineer

July 2004- Dec 2007

- Lead 4-member offshore team on various order, revenue & customer management enterprise level technology initiatives using advanced Java, J2EE, Unix, MySQL, open-source tools (CVS, Apache Struts, JUnit, Hibernate ORM)
- Developed, researched, and documented technical project artifacts and software design documents
- Lead a "first in company" novel proof of concept of an end-to-end enterprise web-based system using Hibernate object
 relational mapping framework for an Africa based telecom client. Customer was highly appreciative of the effort and was
 engaged in long-term contract
- Underwent a 4-week companywide intensive bootcamp on advanced Java. Stood 1st out of 35 trainees

CERTIFICATIONS

• Chartered Financial Analyst (level I) and "Official Anaplan Developer" certification